
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>FINAL PROJECT TITLE</title> 
            <author>??</author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Originally published by</resp>
               <orgName>University of Nebraska College of Journalism</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>   
               <resp>Revised and edited by</resp>
               <name>Ana Chincoa</name>
               <name>Jeff Hill</name>
               <name>Hanna Varilek</name>         
            </respStmt>         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Archives and Special Collections</distributor>    
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>
                  <publisher>The Journalist Vol. TBD No. TBD</publisher>
                  <title>DeCamp: proposed abortion bill restricts use of dangerous methods</title>
                  <author>Lucy Lien</author>
                  <date>Dec. 4, 1974</date>
               </bibl>
               <bibl>ADD THE REST OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC INFO HERE??</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Produced to fulfill requirements of ENGL478-878</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <correction>
               <p>Spelling errors silently corrected</p>
               <p>Hyphenated words at the end of lines silently removed.</p>
            </correction>
         </editorialDecl>        
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <list>
            <item>Document originally created 15 Nov 2022</item>
            <item>
               RECORD MAJOR EDITORIAL PROGRESS HERE
            </item>   
         </list>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <pb facs="Domeier.1.jpg"/>
         
         <div1 type="section1"><head>Armstrong advocates men's lib</head>
            <byline><persName><ref target="PDomeier"></ref>By Shelly Kalkowski</persName></byline>
            <p>Equal rights for women are fine, Charles Armstrong thinks men need to be liberated too.</p>
            <p>“If men can be chauvinists, then so can women,” he said. Armstrong is a former graduate student at the University of Nebraska Lincoln and has done work towards a master's thesis on men's liberation.</p>
            <p>A key element of female chauvinism, according to Armstrong, is the expectation that the man must be the bread winner.</p>
            <p>Other things men need to liberated from are the job stereotypes men are classified under and the idea that a "man" should not openly express his feelings, he said.</p>
            <p>"Women are jumping from the frying pan into the fire when they ask for equal rights,” Armstrong said. “They are going from sexual oppression to economic oppression.”</p>
            <p>The solution, Armstrong said he believes, lies in a guaranteed income that would free men, and women, from economic coercion.</p>
            <p>"Men also need to be liberated from the stereotypes of jock, super-stud and unfeeling machine,” he said.</p>
            <p>Armstrong said an Army manual that said an officer should not be seen carrying a baby was a good example of  this stereotyping.</p>
            <p>"Many people see a man as some sort of machine--an unfeeling robot-- that is not supposed to show any human feelings, such as crying,” Armstrong said. “I see men's liberation as trying to free yourself from the stereotype being imposed upon you.”</p>
            <p>"Maybe what we need is equal rights for chauvinists."</p></div1>
         <div1 type="analysis1"><head>Literary Analysis</head>
            <p>BLAH BLAH BLAH</p>
         </div1>
         
         <pb facs="lastname.2.jpg"/>   
         <div1 type="section2"><head>Armstrong advocates men's lib</head>
            <byline><persName><ref target="xxx">Shelly Kalkowski</ref></persName></byline>
            
         </div1>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>