
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The Journalist</title> 
            <author></author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Originally published by</resp>
               <orgName>University of Nebraska College of Journalism</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>   
            <resp>Revised and edited by</resp>
                  <name>Ana Chincoa</name>
                  <name>Jeff Hill</name>
                  <name>Hanna Varilek</name>         
            </respStmt>         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Archives and Special Collections</distributor>    
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>
               <publisher>The Journalist Vol. 35 No. 9</publisher>
                  <title>Adoption numbers unchanged</title>
               <author>Paul Domier</author>
                  <date>Nov. 17, 1989</date>
            </bibl>
               <bibl></bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Produced to fulfill requirements of ENGL478-878</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <correction>
               <p>Spelling errors silently corrected</p>
               <p>Hyphenated words at the end of lines silently removed.</p>
            </correction>
         </editorialDecl>        
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <list>
            <item>Document originally created 27 Oct 2022</item>
         <item>
          
         </item>   
         </list>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <pb facs="Domeier.1.jpg"/>
         
         <div1 type="section1"><head>Adoption Numbers Unchanged</head>
         <byline><persName><ref target="PDomeier">By Paul Domeier</ref></persName></byline>
         <p>The number of adoptions in Nebraska has not changed since abortion issues came to the
            forefront of public debate again last year, the executive director of the Nebraska
            Children’s Home said. Harris Van Oort said he has not seen a change in the number of
            children put up for adoption or in the number of children placed by his agency since the
            late 1970’s.</p>
         <p>The Nebraska Children’s Home, a state-wide adoption agency with head- quarters in Omaha,
            placed about 225 children in homes each year in the late 1960’s, he said.</p>
         <p>The number of adoptions dropped in the early 1970’s, Van Oort said, after the U.S.
            Supreme Court case Roe vs. Wade, which legalized abortion, and because of changing
            social standards. At about the same time as Roe vs. Wade, society accepted the idea of
            single mothers, he said.</p>
         <p>The affect of single mothers on adop- tons is not easy to trace. Van Oort said. “There
            isn’t a definite time when it became okay for a young lady to be single and a parent,”
            he said.</p>
         <p>The number of children placed by the agency slowly dropped and bottomed out at a little
            more than 100 a year by the late 1970’s, Van Oort said.</p>
         <p> Marcia Blum, the Omaha Child Saving Institute’s family service program supervisor,
            said she hasn’t noticed any effects of the resurgence in the abortion issue.</p>
         <p>She said she thinks that if laws are passed in Nebraska limiting abortion, the number of
            children put up for adop- lion would increase.</p>
         <p>Van Oort said his agency could handle more children being put up for adoption because
            more Nebraska families want to adopt than there are available children.</p></div1>
         <div1 type="analysis1"><head>Literary Analysis</head>
        
         </div1>
         
        <pb facs="lastname.2.jpg"/>   
        <div1 type="section2"><head>HEADLINE</head>
           <byline><persName><ref target="xxx">by</ref></persName></byline>
              
      </div1>
        </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
