
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:lang="en">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>FINAL PROJECT TITLE</title> 
            <author>??</author>
            <respStmt>
               <resp>Originally published by</resp>
               <orgName>University of Nebraska College of Journalism</orgName>
            </respStmt>
            <respStmt>   
               <resp>Revised and edited by</resp>
               <name>Ana Chincoa</name>
               <name>Jeff Hill</name>
               <name>Hanna Varilek</name>         
            </respStmt>         
         </titleStmt>
         
         <publicationStmt>
            <distributor>University of Nebraska-Lincoln Archives and Special Collections</distributor>    
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <listBibl>
               <bibl>
                  <publisher>The Journalist Vol. TBD No. TBD</publisher>
                  <title>Clinic will soon offer vasectomy</title>
                  <author>Nancy Stohs</author>
                  <date>Nov. 20, 1974</date>
               </bibl>
               <bibl>ADD THE REST OF THE BIBLIOGRAPHIC INFO HERE??</bibl>
            </listBibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Produced to fulfill requirements of ENGL478-878</p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <correction>
               <p>Spelling errors silently corrected</p>
               <p>Hyphenated words at the end of lines silently removed.</p>
            </correction>
         </editorialDecl>        
      </encodingDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <list>
            <item>Document originally created 27 Oct 2022</item>
            <item>
               RECORD MAJOR EDITORIAL PROGRESS HERE
            </item>   
         </list>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   
   <text>
      <body>
         <pb facs="Domeier.1.jpg"/>
         
         <div1 type="section1"><head>Clinic will soon offer vasectomy</head>
            <byline><persName><ref target="PDomeier"></ref>By Nancy Stohs</persName></byline>
            <p>Vasectomies soon will be available to low-income persons free of charge or for a small fee at the Planned Parenthood Center, 3830 Adams St.</p>
            <p>The cutting of the sperm duct, which takes about 20 minutes, will be available by appointment one day a week, Steve White center director said.</p>
            <p>Performed by a local urologist or other physician, the operation normally would cost from $100 to $150, he said.</p>
            <p>Planned Parenthood closed its vasectomy clinic about six months ago because it ran out of funds, White said.  It opened in March 1970 on a federal grant for a vasectomy counselor.</p>
            <p>White said it is being reopened in about a month because he believes there’s a need for the operation among low-income persons.</p>
            <p>The physician is volunteering his services, so the only expense to the center will be the cost of supplies, he said.</p>
            <p>White came to Lincoln two months ago from a Planned Parenthood Center in Kansas City, Mo.</p>
            <p>There, as well as in Nebraska, spouse consent isn’t legally required for either a vasectomy or tubal ligation, he said.  Tubal ligation is the sterilization operation for women.</p>
            <p>Most doctors, however, request it as general practice, to prevent marital problems afterward, he said.</p>
            <p>Both operations are relatively simple, he said.</p>
            <p>Only in a small percentage of cases is either operation reversible, he added.</p></div1>
         <div1 type="analysis1"><head>Literary Analysis</head>
            <p>BLAH BLAH BLAH</p>
         </div1>
         
         <pb facs="lastname.2.jpg"/>   
         <div1 type="section2"><head>Clinic will soon offer vasectomy</head>
            <byline><persName><ref target="xxx">Nancy Stohs</ref></persName></byline>
            
         </div1>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>